Guide to the Peter E. Palmquist Collection of Photography and Photographic Formats
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Photographic Prints by Subject, circa 1855-circa 1950; Series VI; 3.1; (8 boxes)
  - Photographic Prints of Children
    - Unidentified Photographers
      - Starbuck, Ferdinand (Box 145, Folder 2127)
      - Unidentified individuals (Box 145, Folder 2128-2129)
    - Copy Photographs
      Copy photographs created by Palmquist of photographs that depict children.
      - Clippings and notes (Box 146, Folder 2130)
      - Negatives (Box 146, Folder 2131)
      - Older children (Box 146, Folder 2132)
      - Infants and Young Children (Box 146, Folder 2133)
      - Children with pets and prized possessions (Box 146, Folder 2134)
      - Children with parents or adults (Box 146, Folder 2135)
      - Post-mortem (Box 146, Folder 2136)
      - Children using footrests (Box 146, Folder 2137)
      - Children with obscured adults (Box 146, Folder 2138)
      - Groups of children with adults (Box 146, Folder 2139)
      - Groups of children without adults (Box 146, Folder 2140)
      - Miscellaneous Reproductions (Box 146, Folder 2141)
- Photographs by Unidentified Photographers, circa 1855-circa 1950; Series VII; 1.5; (5 boxes)
  Series VII is organized into seven subseries:: Photographs Related to Photography, Identified Subjects, Identified Locations, Studio Portraits, Interior Portraits, Exterior Portraits, and Exterior Views.
  This series includes photographs created by unidentified photographs and grouped according to their subjects by Palmquist.
  - Photographs Related to Photography
    - Photographers in the field (Box 147, Folder 2142)
    - Exterior views of photographers' studios (Box 147, Folder 2143)
    - Interior views of photographers' studios (Box 147, Folder 2144)
    - Studio portraits that show backdrops (Box 147, Folder 2145)
  - Identified Subjects
    - Beggs, A. (Box 148, Folder 2146)
    - Crockett, James (Box 148, Folder 2147)
    - Dose, Herman, Jr. (Box 148, Folder 2148)
    - Eby, J. L., Dr. (Box 148, Folder 2149)
    - Finney, W. (Box 148, Folder 2150)
    - Harris, Oscar (Box 148, Folder 2151)
    - Harte, Brette (Box 148, Folder 2152)
    - Hinman, Orrin Clark and Harriet Hinman (Box 148, Folder 2153)
    - Kneeland, John A. (Box 148, Folder 2154)
    - McConnell, Wilbur Ross (Box 148, Folder 2155)
    - Nichols, Wesley (Box 148, Folder 2156)
    - Pergh, Dr. (Box 148, Folder 2157)
    - Russell Family (Box 148, Folder 2158)
    - Saterdahl, Bud and Oddmund (Box 148, Folder 2159)
    - Tanssell, Rufus (Box 148, Folder 2160)
  - Identified Locations
    Arranged geographically.
    - New Jersey
      - Atlantic City (Box 148, Folder 2161)
    - Mexico (Box 148, Folder 2162)
    - Midwestern or South Central United States
      - View of a repair crew for the St. Louis-San Francisco Railway, circa 1890 (Box 148, Folder 2163)
    - New York
      - Niagara Falls (Box 148, Folder 2164)
    - Pennsylvania
      - Addison (Box 148, Folder 2165)
    - Philippines
      - Manila (Box 148, Folder 2166)
  - Studio Portraits
    Arranged under six headings by photographic format: Cartes de Visite, Cabinet Photographs, Card Photographs, Photographic Postcards, Photographic Prints, and Copy Photographs.
    - Cartes de Visite
      - Animals (Box 149, Folder 2167)
      - Children (Box 149, Folder 2168)
      - Couples (Box 149, Folder 2169)
      - Men (Box 149, Folder 2170)
      - Women (Box 149, Folder 2171-2172)
    - Cabinet Photographs
      - Children (Box 149, Folder 2173)
      - Children and animals (Box 149, Folder 2174)
      - Men (Box 149, Folder 2175)
      - Women (Box 149, Folder 2176)
      - Still Lifes (Box 149, Folder 2177)
    - Card Photographs
      - Children (Box 149, Folder 2178)
      - Groups (Box 149, Folder 2179)
      - Women (Box 149, Folder 2180)
    - Photographic Postcards
      - Animals (Box 149, Folder 2181)
      - Bar Tableau (Box 149, Folder 2182)
      - Groups (Box 149, Folder 2183)
      - Men (Box 149, Folder 2184)
      - Still Lifes (Box 149, Folder 2185)
      - Women (Box 149, Folder 2186)
    - Photographic Prints
      - Children (Box 149, Folder 2187)
      - Couples (Box 149, Folder 2188)
      - Men (Box 149, Folder 2189)
      - Women (Box 149, Folder 2190)
      - Chinese Women (Box 149, Folder 2191)
    - Copy Photographs (Box 149, Folder 2192)
  - Interior Portraits
    Arranged under three headings by photographic format: Card Photographs, Photographic Post Cards, and Photographic Prints.
    - Card Photographs
      - Children (Box 150, Folder 2193)
      - Couples (Box 150, Folder 2194)
      - Groups (Box 150, Folder 2195)
    - Photographic Post Cards
      - Couples (Box 150, Folder 2196)
      - Groups (Box 150, Folder 2197)
    - Photographic Prints
      - Groups (Box 150, Folder 2198)
      - Interiors without people (Box 150, Folder 2199)
  - Exterior Portraits
    Arranged under four headings by photographic format: Cabinet Photographs, Card Photographs, Photographic Post Cards, and Photographic Prints.
    - Cabinet Photographs
      - Animals (Box 151, Folder 2200)
    - Card Photographs
      - Animals (Box 151, Folder 2201)
      - Children (Box 151, Folder 2202)
      - Couples (Box 151, Folder 2203)
      - Men (Box 151, Folder 2204)
      - Groups (Box 151, Folder 2205-2207)
      - People with horses (Box 151, Folder 2208)
    - Photographic Postcards
      - Chinese Group (Box 151, Folder 2209)
      - Couples (Box 151, Folder 2210)
      - Groups (Box 151, Folder 2211)
      - People with animals (Box 151, Folder 2212)
    - Photographic Prints
      - American Indian Groups (Box 151, Folder 2213)
      - American Indian Men (Box 151, Folder 2214)
      - Animals (Box 151, Folder 2215)
      - Children (Box 151, Folder 2216)
      - Couples (Box 151, Folder 2217)
      - Groups (Box 151, Folder 2218)
      - People with animals (Box 151, Folder 2219)
      - Still Lifes (Box 151, Folder 2220)
      - Ships and Aboard Ships (Box 151, Folder 2221)
      - Women (Box 151, Folder 2222)
  - Exterior Views
    Arranged under two headings by photographic format: Card Photographs and Photographic Prints
    - Card Photographs
      - Landscapes (Box 151, Folder 2223)
      - Structures (Box 151, Folder 2224)
    - Photographic Prints
      - Landscapes (Box 151, Folder 2225)
      - Structures (Box 151, Folder 2226)
- Realia with Photographs, circa 1850-circa 1950; Series VIII; 12.6; (26 boxes)
  Series VIII is organized into eleven subseries: Photograph Buttons, Photograph Buttons with Ribbons, Photograph Buttons with Mirrors, Photograph Buttons Tape Measures, Photograph Button Plaques, Jewelry for Photographs, Cutting Tools, Photographs on Containers, Ceramic Tiles and a Porcelain Plate with Photographs, Tobacciana, Paperweights, Photographs on Cloth.
  This series consists of human-made objects, referred to as realia, that possess photographic illustrations or decoration.
  - Photograph Buttons
    Organized under three headings: Daguerreotype, Tintypes and Wet Collodion Processes, Celluloid Photograph Buttons
    This subseries includes photograph buttons, which represent photographs mounted on a button mechanism that a wearer may temporarily fasten to the surface of a garment using a safety pin, or a pin formed from wire, a clutch, or other mechanism.
    Photograph buttons evolved with photography, and early forms include daguerreotypes and tintypes. These buttons became particularly popular between 1900 and 1930, when customers supplied a photograph to a manufacturer, who reproduced it as a photograph button.
    - Daguerreotype
      - Oval-shaped daguerreotype photograph button of a man (Box 152, Folder 2227)
    - Tintypes and Wet Collodion Processes
      Arranged chiefly by size from smallest to largest.
      - Circle-shaped tintype photograph button of three people (Box 152, Folder 2228)
      - Oval-shaped tintype photograph button of a man, studded around edges (Box 152, Folder 2229)
      - Bigdon, Frederick A. Circle-shaped tintype photograph button of a man (Box 152, Folder 2230)
      - Oval-shaped tintype photograph button of a man (Box 152, Folder 2231)
      - Circle-shaped tintype photograph button of a man and a boy (Box 152, Folder 2232)
      - Circle-shaped tintype photograph button of a boy in a sailor's hat (Box 152, Folder 2233)
      - Chicago Ferrotype Co., "Tintype Film Chip", circle-shaped tintype photograph button of a man (Box 152, Folder 2234)
      - Oval-shaped pannotype (wet collodion process on leather) photograph button of a man (Box 152, Folder 2235)
      - Circle-shaped tintype photograph button with a boy in a hat and tie, circa 1902 (Box 152, Folder 2236)
    - Celluloid Photograph Buttons
      - Riley-Klotz Manufacturing Co., Circle-shaped photograph button of a woman identified as Virginia Harned, circa 1896 (Box 152, Folder 2237)
      - Hopp?, Charles, Circle-shaped photograph button of an infant (Box 152, Folder 2238)
      - Jewelry Manufacturing Co., Oval-shaped pinlock photograph button of a girl (Box 152, Folder 2239)
      - Circle-shaped pinlock photograph button of a girl (Box 152, Folder 2240)
      - Whitehead & Hoag, Circle-shaped photograph button of a horse and buggy for "McPherson's Third Annual Fall Festival", 1899 September 28-30 (Box 152, Folder 2241)
      - A. Pollard & Co., Circle-shaped photograph button of a waterfall (Box 152, Folder 2242)
      - Circle-shaped photograph button of a man smoking a cigar, circa 1900 (Box 152, Folder 2243)
      - Hursen, O.G., Circle-shaped photograph button of a young man (Box 152, Folder 2244)
      - Circle-shaped pinlock photograph button of a man (Box 152, Folder 2245)
      - Circle-shaped pinlock photograph button of a woman (Box 152, Folder 2246)
      - Circle-shaped pinlock photograph button of two children (Box 152, Folder 2247)
      - Circle-shaped pinlock photograph button of a woman wearing a ruffled collar (Box 152, Folder 2248)
      - Circle-shaped pinlock photograph button of a man wearing a tie (Box 152, Folder 2249)
      - Circle-shaped pinlock photograph button of a young man wearing a tie (Box 152, Folder 2250)
      - Bullard & Moure, Circle-shaped pinlock photograph button of a building with a bust portrait of a man in the foreground (Box 152, Folder 2251)
      - Circle-shaped pinlock photograph button of a woman wearing a high-collared blouse (Box 152, Folder 2252)
      - Circle-shaped pinlock photograph button of a child (Box 152, Folder 2253)
      - Two circle-shaped pinlock photograph buttons of a woman wearing pearls and a bow in her hair (Box 152, Folder 2254)
      - Circle-shaped pinlock photograph button of a woman from behind (Box 152, Folder 2255)
      - Circle-shaped pinlock photograph button of a woman wearing glasses (Box 152, Folder 2256)
      - Circle-shaped pinlock photograph button of a woman with her hair up (Box 153, Folder 2257)
      - Circle-shaped pinlock photograph button of a woman with a bow around her neck (Box 153, Folder 2258)
      - Circle-shaped pinlock photograph button of two girls (Box 153, Folder 2259)
      - Circle-shaped pinlock photograph button of two boys and an infant (Box 153, Folder 2260)
      - Circle-shaped pinlock photograph button of a young man in a fedora (Box 153, Folder 2261)
      - Oval-shaped pinlock photograph button of a man with a walrus mustache (Box 153, Folder 2262)
      - Circle-shaped pinlock photograph button of a man and a woman (Box 153, Folder 2263)
      - Circle-shaped pinlock photograph button of a young man in a uniform hat (Box 153, Folder 2264)
      - Circle-shaped pinlock photograph button of an elderly man with a beard and mustache (Box 153, Folder 2265)
      - Circle-shaped pinlock photograph button of an elderly man with a long beard and mustache (Box 153, Folder 2266)
      - Oval-shaped stick pin photograph button of a man (Box 153, Folder 2267)
      - Circle-shaped stick pin photograph button of a man in a tie, from Moscow, Russia (Box 153, Folder 2268)
      - Circle-shaped stick pin photograph button of a woman in a head scarf (Box 153, Folder 2269)
      - Circle-shaped pinlock photograph button of a woman and child (Box 153, Folder 2270)
      - Circle-shaped pinlock photograph button of a young man in a suit and tie (Box 153, Folder 2271)
      - Circle-shaped pinlock photograph button of a young man wearing his hair with a center-part (Box 153, Folder 2272)
      - Circle-shaped photograph button of a young man (Box 153, Folder 2273)
      - Circle-shaped dangling photograph button of a man with a mustache and beard (Box 153, Folder 2274)
      - Circle-shaped dangling photograph button of a woman (Box 153, Folder 2275)
      - Oval-shaped stick pin photograph button of a boy wearing a bowtie (Box 153, Folder 2276)
      - Circle-shaped photograph button, possibly lapel button or cufflink, of a woman (Box 153, Folder 2277)
      - Three conjoined circles photograph buttons depicting a man, woman, and child, all in hats (Box 153, Folder 2278)
      - Two conjoined circles photograph buttons depicting two boys, one boy is wearing a mortarboard, and the other boy is wearing a sailor's hat (Box 153, Folder 2279)
      - Circle-shaped pinlock photograph button of a woman in lace (Box 153, Folder 2280)
      - Circle-shaped pinlock photograph button of a girl wearing a hat (Box 153, Folder 2281)
  - Photograph Buttons with Tape Measures
    This component consists of measuring tapes with photograph buttons affixed to them.
    - Sellwoods, Circle-shaped photograph button tape measure with views of Ishpeming, Michigan, including the Carnegie Public Library on one side and Main Street on the other (Box 153, Folder 2282)
    - Circle-shaped photograph button tape measure of a young man in a tie (Box 153, Folder 2283)
  - Photograph Buttons with Ribbons (Box 154)
    Photograph buttons in this component have attached fabric ribbons, which often document an event. Occasionally the photograph is affixed to the ribbon
    - Dedication of the Firemen's Monument, Bradford, Pennsylvania; Photograph affixed to the ribbon depicts the monument, 1909 August 12 (Box 154, Folder 2284)
    - Royal Neighbors of America, Candidate for Supreme Recorder; Photograph button depicts a portrait of a woman, identified by a caption printed on the ribbon as Hada M. Burkhart, 1911 (Box 154, Folder 2285)
    - Independent Order of Odd Fellows, 39th Annual Grand Encampment, Medford, Oregon; Photograph button depicts a portrait of a man, 1913 May 20 (Box 154, Folder 2286)
    - Royal Neighbors of America; Photograph button depicts a portrait of a woman, identified by a caption printed on the ribbon as Myra B. Enright, circa 1913 (Box 154, Folder 2287)
    - Independent Order of Odd Fellows of Oregon, Rebekah Assembly, 30th Annual Session, Roseburg, Oregon; Photograph button depicts Rose Palmer, President, while another photograph button depicts a Rose, 1918 May 17 (Box 154, Folder 2288)
    - Independent Order of Odd Fellows of California, Rebekah Assembly, San Francisco; Photograph button depicts a view of an Odd Fellows Lodge, while the ribbon bar identifies the wearer as a past president, 1918 (Box 154, Folder 2289)
    - Royal Neighbors of America, Candidate for Supreme Manager; Photograph button depicts a portrait of a woman, identified by a caption printed in the image as Annah M. Blair, circa 1919 (Box 154, Folder 2290)
    - Royal Neighbors of America, Wisconsin, Candidate for Supreme Manager; Photograph button depicts a portrait of a woman, identified by a caption printed on the ribbon as Eva Child, circa 1919 (Box 154, Folder 2291)
    - Royal Neighbors of America, Candidate for Supreme Manager; Photograph button depicts a portrait of a woman, identified by a caption printed in the image as Alice Gilliland, missing ribbon, circa 1923 (Box 154, Folder 2292)
    - Independent Order of Odd Fellows of Oregon, Rebekah Assembly, 43rd Annual Session, Medford, Oregon; Photograph button depicts a portrait of a woman, 1929 May 21-23 (Box 154, Folder 2293)
    - Independent Order of Odd Fellows of Kentucky, 102nd Annual Session, Lexington, Kentucky; Photograph button depicts a street and buildings, while the ribbon bar identified the wearer as W. B. Day, Watson Lodge, No 32, 1937 October 19-20 (Box 154, Folder 2294)
    - Independent Order of Odd Fellows of Oregon, Rebekah Assembly, 54th Annual Session, Corvallis, Oregon; Photograph button depicts a portrait of a woman, 1940 May 21-23 (Box 154, Folder 2295)
  - Photograph Buttons with Mirrors
    Photograph buttons with mirrors, also known as pocket mirrors, are a form of photograph button with a mirror rather than a pin shell on its back.
    - Circle-shaped photograph button with a mirror and an image of a seated child, with a handle, circa 1900 (Box 155, Folder 2296)
    - Square-shaped photograph button with a mirror and an image of "Miss Willard Boyles, General V.L.B. Sect.": Boyles served as the secretary for the Victory Leaders Band, a yourth organization within the Church of God, circa 1930 (Box 155, Folder 2297)
    - Oval-shaped photograph button with a mirror and an image of a wedding portrait, hand colored, circa 1920 (Box 156, Folder 2298)
    - Oval-shaped photograph button with a mirror and an image of a wedding portrait (Box 156, Folder 2299)
    - Oval-shaped photograph button with a mirror and an image of a woman in a wedding dress, hand colored, circa 1920 (Box 156, Folder 2300)
    - Circle-shaped photograph button with a mirror and an image of a man and woman, toned red, circa 1920 (Box 156, Folder 2301)
    - Oval-shaped photograph button with a mirror and an image of a woman with a guitar outdoors (Box 156, Folder 2302)
    - Oval-shaped photograph button with a mirror and an image of a man wearing a hat, circa 1910 (Box 156, Folder 2303)
    - Oval-shaped photograph button with a mirror and an image of a woman outdoors holding a hat, hand colored, circa 1930 (Box 156, Folder 2304)
    - Circle-shaped photograph button with a mirror and an image of a woman holding flowers, circa 1930 (Box 156, Folder 2305)
    - Oval-shaped photograph button with a mirror and an image of a woman in a wedding dress holding flowers, circa 1940 (Box 156, Folder 2306)
    - Oval-shaped photograph button with a mirror and an image of a woman outdoors, circa 1920-1930 (Box 156, Folder 2307)
    - Oval-shaped photograph button with a mirror and an image of a girl in a white dress (Box 156, Folder 2308)
    - Oval-shaped photograph button with a mirror and an image of a girl wearing bows in her hair (Box 156, Folder 2309)
    - Oval-shaped photograph button with a mirror and an image of a seated child in a bonnet (Box 156, Folder 2310)
    - Oval-shaped photograph button with a mirror and an image of a child in a bonnet in winter (Box 156, Folder 2311)
    - Oval-shaped photograph button with a mirror and an image of a girl seated against a tree (Box 156, Folder 2312)
    - Oval-shaped photograph button with a mirror and an image of a woman in a cap and gown (Box 156, Folder 2313)
    - Oval-shaped photograph button with a mirror and an image of a man and woman standing on a sidewalk (Box 156, Folder 2314)
    - Kesler, William, Oval-shaped photograph button with a mirror and an image of three men standing outside a store, Redding, California, circa 1900 (Box 156, Folder 2315)
    - Whitehead-Hoag, Circle-shaped photograph button with a mirror and an image of an infant, with a notice for State Life Insurance Co., Indianapolis, Indiana, circa 1920 (Box 156, Folder 2316)
    - Circle-shaped photograph button with a mirror and an image of a woman, hand colored, with a handle, circa 1890-1900 (Box 156, Folder 2317)
  - Photograph Button Plaques
    This subseries consists of photograph button plaques arranged chiefly by size from smallest to largest followed by Sales Kits from the Cruver Manufacturing Company.
    This subseries consists of photograph button plaques, also referred to as photograph medallions, are large photograph buttons. Most incorporate a photograph with a decorative border, and a back with hook for hanging or an easel stand. This subseries also includes sales kits distributed by the Cruver Manufacturing Company for marketing the plaques.
    - Oval-shaped photograph button plaque of a scene of a pond in a forest, circa 1900 (Box 157, Folder 2318)
    - Rectangle-shaped photograph button plaque of two boys, one seated, one standing (Box 157, Folder 2319)
    - Oval-shaped photograph button plaque of a man in a United States Navy cap and a woman in a veil, with a stand (Box 157, Folder 2320)
    - Oval-shaped photograph button plaque of a woman in pearls from behind (Box 157, Folder 2321)
    - Oval-shaped photograph button plaque of an infant lying down, framed by flowers (Box 157, Folder 2322)
    - Rectangle-shaped photograph button plaque of a man in a suit and tie, with a stand (Box 157, Folder 2323)
    - Circle-shaped photograph button plaque of a girl in a ruffled dress, leaning on a chair (Box 157, Folder 2324)
    - Circle-shaped photograph button plaque of a portrait of a woman with short hair (Box 157, Folder 2325)
    - Columbia Portrait Company, Circle-shaped photograph button plaque of a man and child (Box 157, Folder 2326)
    - Columbia Medallion Studios, Circle-shaped photograph button plaque of two boys in sailor caps (Box 157, Folder 2327)
    - Rectangle-shaped photograph button plaque of a woman standing, hand colored (Box 157, Folder 2328)
    - Circle-shaped photograph button plaque of three girls seated on steps (Box 157, Folder 2329)
    - Circle-shaped photograph button plaque of a young man in a suit and tie (Box 158, Folder 2330)
      Contact prints of the photograph affixed to the recto of the plaque
    - Circle-shaped photograph button plaque of a woman with puffy sleeves (Box 158, Folder 2331)
    - Columbia Medallion Studios, Circle, Photograph button plaque of a child in a toque standing by a car (Box 158, Folder 2332)
    - Columbia Portrait Company, Circle-shaped photograph button plaque of a woman and two children (Box 158, Folder 2333)
    - Circle-shaped photograph button plaque with separate photographs of a man, woman, boy, and girl, as well as flowers in the background (Box 158, Folder 2334)
    - Columbia Medallion Studios, Circle-shaped photograph button plaque of a girl with a pink bow in her hair and on her blouse, hand colored (Box 158, Folder 2335)
    - Columbia Portrait Company, Circle-shaped photograph button plaque of a woman with a bows in her hair and on her blouse (Box 158, Folder 2336)
    - Circle-shaped photograph button plaque of a woman with long hair seated in the grass outdoors (Box 158, Folder 2337)
    - Columbia Medallion Studios, Circle-shaped photograph button plaque of a woman (Box 158, Folder 2338)
    - Armour Soap Works, Circle, Photograph button plaque of a seated infant (Box 158, Folder 2339)
    - Columbia Portrait Company, Circle-shaped photograph button plaque of a woman in lace posed sitting (Box 158, Folder 2340)
    - Van Ralty Studios, Oval-shaped photograph button plaque of a woman in a hat and glasses (Box 158, Folder 2341)
    - Oval-shaped photograph button plaque of a man in uniform, shaking of a dog seated on a chair (Box 159, Folder 2342)
    - Circle-shaped photograph button plaque of a child in a hat posed standing with metal cans outdoors (Box 159, Folder 2343)
    - Oval-shaped photograph button plaque of a man with a large mustache and wearing a suit and tie (Box 159, Folder 2344)
    - Circle-shaped photograph button plaque of a woman in a blue dress, hand colored (Box 159, Folder 2345)
    - Columbia Medallion Studios, Circle-shaped photograph button plaque of a boy playing a snare drum with a dog at his feet (Box 159, Folder 2346)